The final point I want to make about
this is a sobering one which is about
not getting caught up in the hype of
agent coding. Now look generally I am a
huge fan very passionate about the
impact that LLM can make to software
development but there is certainly some
hype out there that is unwarranted.
There are some tasks for sure where
using LLM can make it order of magnitude
faster to deliver. If you're building a
boilerplate React front end, which is
going to involve a lot of componentry
and you've got a very good sense of what
you want the UI to look like, an LLM can
do that in a matter of minutes when it
would take a great front-end person
maybe maybe a day and it would take me
several weeks. So certainly for me,
order of magnitude difference. But there
are some tasks where LLMs are only
incrementally faster than just doing it
yourself. And indeed, I've had
experiences where I feel like it has
actually slowed me down because I'd had
to go in and rewrite something where
there was a a mistake, a very subtle
mistake that I wasn't expecting. Netnet,
there is no question that LLMs are a
huge value ad and that I'm able to
achieve a lot more as a result of using
them. How much more depends critically
on the project. more highly innovative
projects with larger code bases and the
improvement becomes more incremental.
Starting out with something completely
new where it's a complete green fields
project and where I I'm working on
something where there's plenty of
boilerplate code in there like like a as
I say a sort of boilerplate React front
end. That's the kind of thing where LLMs
can change the game. It uh days turn
into minutes. It can be that radical. So
there are both extremes there as a in in
aggregate for me it is a multiplier but
it's not a 10x and that's something
which I think we all have to have that
kind of of very reasonable grounded
opinion and be sure to set the record
straight if people uh there there's
people that are that are too caught up
in the hype and there are also now
there's a sort of movement of people who
are anti- AI perhaps because they
they've they've got frustrated by the
hype and they've had some negative
experiences. So, it's incumbent on us to
do the work, to learn about these tools,
to use them, and then to set the record
straight, both the pros and the cons, be
able to explain where they are highly
beneficial and where they still have
some room to grow. And as the final
topic for today, I have lots of courses
which go into tons of detail about the
different LLMs out there, but it's worth
having a quick mention of it because
this is this is such an important part
of what we're going to be doing. There's
a website called artificialanalysis.ai
and I have that right up here to show
you. And this is one. This is one I know
that I know that people don't use
bookmarks anymore. If I if I say you
should you should add this to your
bookmarks. I sound like I'm I still use
Facebook, but but you should add this to
your bookmarks. Only have one bookmark.
It should be artificialis.ai.
Here it is. And uh yeah, this is this is
a website that allows you to compare the
different models. And when you bring up
artificial analysis.ai AI, you're going
to see something different to me because
models change so fast. And you're going
to be lucky that you're going to see
you're going to have even better
experiences than me. But what you you
find on this page is various different
ways to compare the different LLMs out
there in terms of intelligence and speed
and price uh dimensioned in all sorts of
different ways and we'll look at some of
them now. So this is the uh intelligence
index which is the single uh
encompassing score from this these
people artificial analysis on how smart
a model is and what you'll see is that
in top position are the models that I
mentioned all sort of around November
2025 which was a point of inflection
when suddenly uh these agentic these
these coding agents really had a step
change in terms of how much you can
trust them. And there are still still
some naysayers out there who who are
still burnt, have scar tissue from how
the models used to be before November
2025. And you have to sort of encourage
them to come back and give it another
try because so much has changed since
then. And here we have like we we used
yesterday GPT 5.2 uh from from OpenAI
that is that is considered at least by
this index to be the smartest model.
Claude Opus 4.5 comes next. It is my
model of choice, but that's partly
because I use it within Claude code and
that whole environment is so geared
towards productive coding. And then uh
GPT 5.2 codeex is just a variant of GPT
5.2 that's more designed for for coding.
And Gemini 3 Pro is of course Google's
latest strongest model, at least as of
now. And that also scores quite well.
And then before that, you see where the
models used to be and you can see it
made a big jump suddenly in uh in in
around uh uh November of last year. And
I would encourage you to spend time on
this site. I'm not going to go through
it now, but you'll see so much here,
including this amazing chart that shows
front-end model intelligence over time.
It does have this slightly spooky way of
appearing to be on a curve upwards in
terms of intelligence. I personally
think that that's because there's been a
couple of bumps. One of them came in the
last year or so with this big boost
because of these new reasoning
techniques. So, so, so I don't think
that curve is going to continue to
steepen, but you'll be able to see,
you'll be able to go and look right now
and see whether my prediction is right.
Um, I expect to see uh more improvement
this year, but but not a continual
sharpening slope. So you will have
better models than me and you should see
that in your outputs. So have a look
through this site. You'll also see a
number of these individual tests
including a specific coding related test
that you'll see here to see what comes
through strongest in terms of of coding
and here in terms of being able to use
tools and what comes through most
strongly. And you'll you'll see here
that this this open source model GLM47
from Z.AI AI uh the the Chinese AI
startup is uh is really really strong
there. So spend some time look at this
uh and uh use this incredible resource
this amazing website to learn more about
the different models and the different
providers and find out how much the
world has changed since since I look at
artificial analysis.ai right here. And
with that, that wraps up day two of week
one. We've covered the foundations you
put up with me talking more than I'll
talk in any other point in this course.
So thank you. And tomorrow we're going
to look at tools, tools, tools. We're
going to look at at cursor, co-pilot,
codeex, anti-gravity. It's going to be
really fun. I can't wait to show you all
of that. But for now, take a moment to
celebrate. You're 13% way through this
journey. And we've got lots of great
things ahead.